Hello, my name is Pavlina Todorova and today I am going to show you how to draw a smile emoji with Inkscape.
So at first when you open inkscape you will see the white page that we use for painting.
To create a smile emoji click on the Circle from the Tool box on the left and fill it with yellow color.
For better shaping use the Control bar on the top to set the size and the coordinates of the object.
To draw an eye create an ellipse. Fill it with brown color and set the size and the coordinates.
Then again create another ellipse but place it horizontal.
Use the Path from the Menu and click Difference to cut the eye.
Now make Duplicate to draw the other eye and set its coordinates.
Let’s continue with the mouth.
Create an ellipse. Fill it with red color and set the width and height to be perfect for a smile.
Then create another ellipse.
Place it on the red one and make their difference to get the smile.
The perfect emoji has white teeth.
Click on the Pen Tool and make a straight line in the center of the smile.
With the help of the Node Tool pull the straight line down.
Then fill the first part of the mouth with white color.
Now the smile emoji is ready.